穿越分界线
CROSSING THE LINE
梅耶在战俘营
Meyers' in the Stalag.
今天算完了
算了 叫贝尔蒂耶来
That's the day shot. Ah well, too bad, call Berthier.
司令官
Kommandant.
用来扩建营房…
就是原来的男校
For the extension of the barracks....the old boys school.
当然 货款以马克结算
不是法郎
Obviously, this work will be paid for
in marks not francs.
要是给德国人干活
他们总该供应汽油吧
I suppose if we're working for the
Germans they'll cough up the petrol.
倒不失为一笔好买卖
That's not a bad scam.
怎么样 小甜心？
So, Te Quiero ?
凯尔韦恩警长托我帮个忙
马尔凯蒂探长没地方住
Commissaire de Kerven has asked a favour.
He has a problem lodging Inspecteur Marchetti.
市长先生 昨晚一条德军
军用电话线被人破坏了…
Monsieur le Maire, a German military
telephone cable was sabotaged last night...
你没有尽到职责
You're not playing the game.
想想你之前一直纠缠我
说什么战俘包裹的事！
When I think of you pestering me with stories
of parcels for your POWs !
市长先生 我通知你 从今天起
另行通知前 宵禁提前至18点
Monsieur le Maire, be informed, that from today
until further notice, the curfew starts at 18:00h.
此外 你要拟定一份名单
列出二十位户主的姓名
Henceforth you will establish a list
of the names, of 20 heads of family.
我还没来得及
祝贺你获得这一任命
I haven't had the opportunity
to congratulate you on your nomination.
要不是电缆被割了
他们也不会来找我们麻烦
If it hadn't been cut they wouldn't
be coming to crap all over us.
副省长先生
我不太明白您的意思
I don't follow you clearly Monsieur le Sous-Préfet.
恕我直言 警长
你六月份的表现可不光彩
Excuse me Commissaire, you didn't
exactly shine in June.
市长先生 如果我们为了从
德国人那换好处而办案 就完了
Monsieur le Maire, if we start to do police work
to obtain something from the Boches, we're done for.
…然后交给法国法庭审判
这样两头都赢
...and bring him before a French Court.
That way we win on all counts.
别错过这次将功赎罪的机会
凯尔韦恩
Don't miss this opportunity
to redeem yourself de Kervern.
抱歉 没什么好消息
您佃农洛兰·日尔曼的妻子有封信
I'm sorry, I don't have good news.
I have a letter for the wife of your tenant, Lorrain Germain.
就一份制式公函
拖了够久的！
It's a form letter. They took their time !
亲爱的 作为镇上的首席长官
我必须排在第一个
Darling, as First Magistrate of the Commune,
I must be first on the list.
听人说起过
I hear folk talk about it.
我在睡觉 没听到声音
I sleep. Not hear noise.
校长有权在任何纪律审查中
陪同教师出席
The head has the right to assist a teacher
in all disciplinary proceedings.
…六月十二日博尔德里小姐的
所有行为 都是在您管辖下发生的 不是吗？
...all that Mademoiselle Borderie did on June 12th,
she did under your authority. Didn't she ?
莫尔朗热夫人
您是犹太人 对吧？
You are Jewish, Madame Morhange, I believe ?
或许您更喜欢斯宾诺莎？
You prefer Spinoza, perhaps ?
因为你的一时任性
法兰西失去了两个孩子
Because of your whim, France has lost
two of its children.
说到底 让一个连…
都分不清的人当老师
Finally, I hardly see how one can let someone teach,
who can't see the difference between...
遇到这种事 绝对不能签字
你现在真的有麻烦了
In these cases you should never sign anything.
You're really in trouble now.
她刚失去了丈夫 你闭嘴
She just lost her husband, so shut up.
你真觉得有小偷会挑
二十个德国兵睡觉的地方下手！
You really think that a burglar picked a place
where 20 German soldiers were sleeping !
这些人将自愿负责
每晚看守军用电缆
They're the names of volunteers who are accountable
for the nightly guarding of military cables.
同志 这是党的命令
Comrade, it's a Party Order.
那位同志化名埃德蒙
你化名保尔
The Comrade will call himself Edmond.
You will call yourself Paul.
偷东西不好
但告密更可耻 记住了
It's not nice to steal but it's worse to squeal.
Never forget that.
这完全是多此一举
就是为了羞辱我们 耀武扬威
It's useless. It's done especially to
humiliate us, and make us feel they're the masters.
也不全是坏消息！
省府和副省府决定给我们补贴
There's not only bad news ! The Préfecture
and Sous-Préfecture have decided to compensate us.
被迫像新兵一样站岗
真是不可思议
It's still incredible to be forced
to mount guard like squaddies.
大概是被上级训了一顿
I suppose he had his chain jerked by his superiors.
仗打输了 就得设法赢得和平
We lost the war. We have to try and win the peace.
这个人心脏病发作了
可能会死
But this man is having a heart attack. He may die.
他跟你说了…警察！
法国警察 看在上帝份上！
He told you... Police ! French Police, in the Name of God !
这里是非占领区
我们用法国时间 现在九点
Here in the Unoccupied Zone we live
on French Time. It's 9 o'clock.
我们坚持苏德互不侵犯条约的路线
斯大林同志自有打算
We hold to the Line of the Nazi-Soviet Pact.
Comrade Stalin knows what he's doing.
贝当 赖伐尔 两百家族…
Pétain, Laval, the 200 Families...
伦敦和维希的财阀们
The plutocrats of London and Vichy.
德国人…是个典型的伪命题
The Germans ...  are a typical false problem.
他们是穿军装的工人 保尔
跟我们一样的工人
They are Workers in uniform, Paul.
Workers like us.
因为在占领区
问题是德国人 不是贝当
Because in the Occupied Zone the
Germans are the problem, not Pétain.
我要告诉你 你被任命为
维勒纳夫区的政治负责人
I've to tell you that you've been named
political head of the Villeneuve sector.
万一形势变了…有同志
埋伏在那里 对我们没坏处
And if that changes... we won't be unhappy
to have Comrades in place, working for them.
克列孟梭说得对
法兰西已经死了
Clémenceau was right, France is dead.
这汇率可不利于法德友谊啊
The exchange rate does nothing
for Franco-German friendship.
不是黑市 只是互相帮忙
Not black market. Just help each other.
官价是店铺的价格
Official price for shops.
别说了 马雷克 这套说辞
我们听够了 火腿从哪来的？
Stop it Marek, we know the song, words and music.
Where did you get the ham ?
不是买的 是送的
Not buy. Is gift.
让死人开口说话
Making the dead speak.
第一 对警察撒谎 第二 盗窃
第三 黑市交易 事情大了
One, lying to the Police;
Two, theft; Three, black market.
This is starting to be a big deal.
没偷 是捡的 没偷！
No stolen. Found, no stolen !
吵闹声 我到窗口 看见人跑
Commotion. I go window. See run.
承认偷了大件却不认小件
我从业以来从没见过
So a guy who admits stealing the big thing but not the
little ones, I've never seen that in all my career.
他的命运该由法官来定
不是我们…
It's for the judge to decide his fate, not us...
我去通知副省长 我们找到了
电缆损坏事件的责任人之一
I'm going to warn the Sous-Préfet
that we've found one of those responsible
for the damage to the cable.
但我不能保证
最后 一张永久优先通行证…
But I promise nothing.
Finally a permanent priority Ausweiss...
凭这个你可以
不限次数地穿越分界线
With that you can cross the Line
as many times as necessary.
我来提走嫌犯马雷克·杜齐亚克
德军以破坏罪通缉他
I've come to take charge of the prisoner, Marek Dutchya,
who's sought by the German Army for sabotage.
我有正式命令要提走此人
由区司令官赫尔穆特·冯·里特尔签署
I have a formal order to take charge of this man.
An order signed by Kreiskommandant Helmut von Ritter.
这违反了停战协定
It's a violation of the Armistice Convention.
德国人要他 我们何必客气
他是黑市贩子 小偷 还是外国人
The Germans want him. We're not going to
stand on ceremony, he's a black marketeer,
a thief, and what's more, a foreigner.
法兰西国家维护法治
The French State upholds the Rule of Law.
冯·里特尔说包裹的事可以解决
宵禁也改回20点
Von Ritter tells me the parcel issue can be sorted out.
As for the curfew, it goes back to 20:00h.
不公平！我不是小偷
It not fair ! Not thief.
你说过 如果我说出去
就会有坏事发生…
You said that if I said anything,
something bad would happen...